[
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "How many times has Kirk ripped his shirt in this series?",
    "Answer 1": 10,
    "Answer 2": 5,
    "Answer 3": 13,
    "Answer 4": 8,
    "Correct Answer": 13,
    "Narrative": "Considering that there were only 79 episodes, it seems like a considerable number, doesn't it?"
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "The Corbomite Maneuver",
    "Question": "What organization did Balok say he represented?",
    "Answer 1": "The Fesarius",
    "Answer 2": "The First Federation",
    "Answer 3": "Cosmic Syndicate",
    "Answer 4": "Celestial Union",
    "Correct Answer": "The First Federation",
    "Narrative": "In this episode, the commander of the \"Fesarius\" was found to be a child-like alien who loved\n the beverage know as \"Tranya\"."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Where No Man Has Gone Before",
    "Question": "In this episode, two crew were endowed with God-like powers. Which\ntwo crew?",
    "Answer 1": "Gary Mitchell and Elizabeth \nDenher",
    "Answer 2": "Sulu and Chekov",
    "Answer 3": "Kirk and Spock",
    "Answer 4": "Scotty and McCoy",
    "Correct Answer": "Gary Mitchell and Elizabeth \nDenher",
    "Narrative": "The two crew were endowed with God-like powers due to a force field that the Enterprise passed\nthrough. Mitchell became power-mad, while Dehner was able to control her response."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "The Naked Time",
    "Question": "Crewman Kevin Riley barricaded himself in Engineering and repatedly\nsang the song \"I'll Take You Home Again Kathleen\". Which of these\nsingers also performed this song?",
    "Answer 1": "Elvis Presley",
    "Answer 2": "Dean Martin",
    "Answer 3": "Jerry Lee Lewis",
    "Answer 4": "Tom Jones",
    "Correct Answer": "Elvis Presley",
    "Narrative": "This song was included on Elvis Presley's album \"Fool\"."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "City on the Edge of Forever",
    "Question": "What drug did Doctor McCoy accidentally inject himself with in\nthis episode",
    "Answer 1": "Cordrazine",
    "Answer 2": "Tri-Ox",
    "Answer 3": "Hyronalin",
    "Answer 4": "Leporazine",
    "Correct Answer": "Cordrazine",
    "Narrative": "This drug, when given in large amount s, can cause serious mental instability. In this case, it caused McCoy to go\ntemporarily insane which ultimately made him jump through the \"Guardian of Forever\" into Earth's past."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "The Doomsday Machine",
    "Question": "In this episode, what happened to Commodore Decker's crew?",
    "Answer 1": "They transported to the surface\n of a planet",
    "Answer 2": "They abondoned ship in\nescape pods",
    "Answer 3": "They transported to another\nship",
    "Answer 4": "They stayed onboard",
    "Correct Answer": "They transported to the surface\n of a planet",
    "Narrative": "They crew transported to the surface of the planet that Decker's ship was orbiting. Ultimately, the Doomsday\nMachine destroyed the planet, resulting in the death of Decker's entire crew."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Catspaw",
    "Question": "In this episode, two aliens took human form and had magical powers.\nWhat device gave them this ability?",
    "Answer 1": "Transmuter",
    "Answer 2": "Universal modulator",
    "Answer 3": "Dimensional alterator",
    "Answer 4": "Cosmic resonator",
    "Correct Answer": "Transmuter",
    "Narrative": "This device was used by \"Sylvia\" to transform herself into a cat, and into a woman. Sylvia and Korob were actually creatures\nthat could not survive the conditions on the planet without the Transmuter, and they ultimately died when Kirk destroyed it."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "A Piece of the Action",
    "Question": "In this episode, Kirk teaches his captors a fictional card game. What\nwas the name of this game?",
    "Answer 1": "Stellar Flush",
    "Answer 2": "Fizbin",
    "Answer 3": "Galactic Bluff",
    "Answer 4": "Cosmic Poker",
    "Correct Answer": "Fizbin",
    "Narrative": "In this ridiculous game, some of the rules are: The second card is turned up, except on Tuesdays, If the player gets 2 Jacks, they get\nanother card \"if it's dark outside\", and the best cards to get are a King and Queen, except at night, when you want a Queen and\na Jack."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Specter of the Gun",
    "Question": "In this episode, what was the name of the alien species the crew of\nthe Enterprise encountered?",
    "Answer 1": "Romulans",
    "Answer 2": "Melkotions",
    "Answer 3": "Metrons",
    "Answer 4": "Talosians",
    "Correct Answer": "Melkotions",
    "Narrative": "The \"Melkots\", as a result of the Enterprise crew ignoring a warning not to approach their planet, caused the landing party to\nparticipate in a deadly \"Shootout at the O.K. Corral\" simulation."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Miri",
    "Question": "In this episode, the crew encounters children who, when they reach\nadulthood turn into what the children call what?",
    "Answer 1": "Grups",
    "Answer 2": "Oldies",
    "Answer 3": "Ageds",
    "Answer 4": "Adulties",
    "Correct Answer": "Grups",
    "Narrative": "Obviously a warped version of \"grown-ups\". The inhabitants of an almost identical Earth planet attempted to create immortality,\nand instead killed all of the adults, but kept the children young for hundreds of years. In the end, once they did reach adulthood,\nthey also died quickly."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Shore Leave",
    "Question": "In this episode, Kirk finds someone from his Starfleet Acadamy days,\nand has a prolonged fight with him. Who is this person?",
    "Answer 1": "Finnegan",
    "Answer 2": "Gary Mitchell",
    "Answer 3": "Ben Finney",
    "Answer 4": "Carol Marcus",
    "Correct Answer": "Finnegan",
    "Narrative": "An \"upper-classman\", Finnegan tormented Kirk in his acadamy days. In this episode, Kirk gets a chance to \"get even\"."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "The Squire of Gothos",
    "Question": "In this episode, Kirk and his landing party encounter an alien\nentity who claims to have studied Earth's past. Who is this alien?",
    "Answer 1": "Vina",
    "Answer 2": "Trelane",
    "Answer 3": "Flint",
    "Answer 4": "Sargon",
    "Correct Answer": "Trelane",
    "Narrative": "Although Trelane appears to be a powerful alien, with powers that are almost magical, he is later found to be an immature\nmember of a powerful species, and treats his \"pets\" and \"toys\" poorly."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "The Changeling",
    "Question": "In this episode, \"Nomad\" has incorrectly idenfied Kirk as its creator.\nKirk has to destroy Nomad before it destroys the Enterprise. How does\nKirk accomplish this?",
    "Answer 1": "Confuses Nomad with logic",
    "Answer 2": "Tricks Nomad into \"beaming\"\ninto a star",
    "Answer 3": "Uploaded a virus into Nomad",
    "Answer 4": "Generated a strong\nmagnetic field into Nomad.",
    "Correct Answer": "Confuses Nomad with logic",
    "Narrative": "Because Nomad has mistakenly identified Kirk as \"The Kirk\", his creator, and Nomad values \"perfection\", Kirk is able to\ncause Nomad to destroy itself as a result of its \"imperfection\"."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "Dr. Richard Daystrom introduced M5, a new computer on the\nEnterprise. What type of computer was this?",
    "Answer 1": "Multitronic",
    "Answer 2": "Duotronic",
    "Answer 3": "Bio-Neural",
    "Answer 4": "Positronic",
    "Correct Answer": "Multitronic",
    "Narrative": "Multitronic computers become the future of computing in Star Trek. They were a significant improvement from the\nprevious Duotronic computer systems. Of course, this doesn't occur until well after the self-preservation and destroying of\nother Starfleet vessel issues were ironed out."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "How many times does Doctor McCoy claim, \"I'm a Doctor, not a....\"?",
    "Answer 1": 5,
    "Answer 2": 10,
    "Answer 3": 20,
    "Answer 4": 11,
    "Correct Answer": 11,
    "Narrative": "11 times in 79 episodes. That's pretty significant. He has claimed not to be a bricklayer, an escalator and an engineer, \namong other things."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "What was another name for the Pon Farr, that caused Vulcans to\nmate or die?",
    "Answer 1": "Hot blood",
    "Answer 2": "Blood fever",
    "Answer 3": "Death curse",
    "Answer 4": "Mating fever",
    "Correct Answer": "Blood fever",
    "Narrative": "In Amok Time, Spock must mate or die. That sucks."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Particles",
    "Question": "What did the \"Doomsday Machine\" use to destroy planets?",
    "Answer 1": "Antiproton beam",
    "Answer 2": "Antimatter beam",
    "Answer 3": "Antineutron beam",
    "Answer 4": "Antithoron beam",
    "Correct Answer": "Antiproton beam",
    "Narrative": "Commodore Decker described the beam fired from the Doomsday Machine as antiprotons - \"Absolutely pure\"."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Planets",
    "Question": "In which star system is the planet Vulcan located?",
    "Answer 1": "40 Eridani",
    "Answer 2": "Tau Ceti",
    "Answer 3": "Wolf 359",
    "Answer 4": "Barnard's star",
    "Correct Answer": "40 Eridani",
    "Narrative": "This is actually a real star system, located approximately 16.5 light years from earth."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "General Orders",
    "Question": "General order 7 prohibits travel to which planet?",
    "Answer 1": "Talos IV",
    "Answer 2": "Ceti Alpha V",
    "Answer 3": "40 Eridani",
    "Answer 4": "Ceti Alpha IV",
    "Correct Answer": "Talos IV",
    "Narrative": "Due to the Talosians ability to telepathically induce hallucinations and make people believe what is not true, Starfleet\ninstituted General Order 7, prohibiting travel to that planet \"for any reason\"."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "Who played Spock's father and also a Romulan Commander?",
    "Answer 1": "Mark Lenard",
    "Answer 2": "Morgan Woodward",
    "Answer 3": "Barbara Babcock",
    "Answer 4": "William Campbell",
    "Correct Answer": "Mark Lenard",
    "Narrative": "Although all of these actors have played multiple roles in Star Trek: The Original Series, Lenard was Spock's father and also portrayed\nthe Romulan Commander in the episode Balance of Terror."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Planets",
    "Question": "Who inhabits the planet Holberg 917G?",
    "Answer 1": "Flint",
    "Answer 2": "Harry Mudd",
    "Answer 3": "Zephram Cochrane",
    "Answer 4": "Trelane",
    "Correct Answer": "Flint",
    "Narrative": "Flint was an immortal human who claimed to also be Mozart, and a number of other significant people in Earth's history."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Technology",
    "Question": "What species language is problematic for the universal translator?",
    "Answer 1": "Romulan",
    "Answer 2": "Tholian",
    "Answer 3": "Metrons",
    "Answer 4": "Talosians",
    "Correct Answer": "Tholian",
    "Narrative": "The universal translator had difficulty with the Tholians language, perhaps due to their unique structure."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Production",
    "Question": "What studio originally produced this series?",
    "Answer 1": "Desilu",
    "Answer 2": "20th Century Fox",
    "Answer 3": "Warner Brothers",
    "Answer 4": "Screen Gems",
    "Correct Answer": "Desilu",
    "Narrative": "Desilu was owned by Lucille Ball, along with her husband, Desi Arnez."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Production",
    "Question": "Although never used, this series opening music had lyrics. Who wrote\nthese lyrics?",
    "Answer 1": "Alexander Courage",
    "Answer 2": "D.C. Fontana",
    "Answer 3": "Gene Roddenberry",
    "Answer 4": "Leonard Nimoy",
    "Correct Answer": "Gene Roddenberry",
    "Narrative": "The lyrics were never intended to be sung. Reportedly, Roddenberry only wanted them so he could pocket some profit from them\nas a co-writer credit."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Technology",
    "Question": "What does dilithium do in propulsion systems?",
    "Answer 1": "Stabilize and focus matter and\nantimatter",
    "Answer 2": "Provides fuel for the warp\ndrive",
    "Answer 3": "Cools the matter/antimatter\ncontainment chamber",
    "Answer 4": "Creates a warp field",
    "Correct Answer": "Stabilize and focus matter and\nantimatter",
    "Narrative": "Dilithium acts as a stabilizer for the warp engines by focusing the matter/antimatter reaction to contain the massive energy\noutput necessary for warp propulsion."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "When Wil Wheaton asked for a raise, what did the studio offer him\ninstead of a monetary raise?",
    "Answer 1": "A promotion to Lieutenant",
    "Answer 2": "More screen time",
    "Answer 3": "Creative input",
    "Answer 4": "Directorial opportunities",
    "Correct Answer": "A promotion to Lieutenant",
    "Narrative": "Wheaton allegedly told the producers  \"So what should I tell my landlord when I can't pay my rent? 'Don't worry, I just made Lieutenant'?!"
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "Props",
    "Question": "After the second season, production planned to remove Geordi's VISOR\ndue to surgery to restore his natural eyesight. Why didn't this occur?",
    "Answer 1": "The actor liked the VISOR",
    "Answer 2": "Storytelling potential",
    "Answer 3": "It made him a positive role-model\nfor the disabled community",
    "Answer 4": "Fan attachment",
    "Correct Answer": "It made him a positive role-model\nfor the disabled community",
    "Narrative": "Recognizing that the character had become a positive role model for the disabled community, producers dropped the plan."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "Gene Roddenberry initially refused to cast Patrick Stewart as Captain\nPicard for a number of reasons.  Who campaigned for Stewart leading\nto the acceptance of his casting?",
    "Answer 1": "Robert H. Justman",
    "Answer 2": "Jonathan Frakes",
    "Answer 3": "Brent Spiner",
    "Answer 4": "Michael Piller",
    "Correct Answer": "Robert H. Justman",
    "Narrative": "Roddenberry wanted a character who was younger, with a full head of hair."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "What was \"The Picard Maneuver\"?",
    "Answer 1": "A tactical combat maneuver",
    "Answer 2": "Pulling down his uniform tunic",
    "Answer 3": "A diplomatic strategy",
    "Answer 4": "An emergency protocol",
    "Correct Answer": "A tactical combat maneuver",
    "Narrative": "Although it has been referenced as Picard pulling his tunic down, it is actually a tactical battle manuever. It was first employed by Picard while serving\nonboard the Stargazer. During a battle with the Ferengi, he made it appear that his ship was in two places at the same time, confusing the Ferengi,\nand allowing him to destroy their ship."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "Aliens",
    "Question": "The Borg became the main adversary in this series. What species was\noriginally intended to fulfil this role?",
    "Answer 1": "Ferengi",
    "Answer 2": "Q",
    "Answer 3": "Breen",
    "Answer 4": "Species 8472",
    "Correct Answer": "Ferengi",
    "Narrative": "Although they ended up as more of a comic relief, the Ferengi were originally intended to be the main adversarial species in this\nseries."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "The Inner Light",
    "Question": "Which character in this episode is Patrick Stewart's real-life son?",
    "Answer 1": "Young Batai (Kamin's son)",
    "Answer 2": "Batai (Kamin's friend)",
    "Answer 3": "Administrator",
    "Answer 4": "Protector",
    "Correct Answer": "Young Batai (Kamin's son)",
    "Narrative": "Patrick Stewart's real-life son, Daniel Stewart. In the episode, he was named after Kamin's friend, Batai."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "The Big Goodbye",
    "Question": "In this episode, Picard portrays a private detective in a holodeck\nsimulation. What character does Picard play?",
    "Answer 1": "Sherlock Holmes",
    "Answer 2": "Dixon Hill",
    "Answer 3": "James Bond",
    "Answer 4": "Sam Spade",
    "Correct Answer": "Dixon Hill",
    "Narrative": "Dixon Hill embodies the quintessential characteristics of a hard-boiled detective from 1940s noir fiction. He is tough, street-smart, and \noperates in a gritty, urban setting."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "The Arsenal of Freedom",
    "Question": "What caused the demise of the people of the planet Minos in this\nepisode?",
    "Answer 1": "A natural disaster",
    "Answer 2": "Their own weapons turned\non them",
    "Answer 3": "A massive solar flare",
    "Answer 4": "Alien invasion",
    "Correct Answer": "Their own weapons turned\non them",
    "Narrative": "The Minosians created a weapon that was able to learn and adapt, which ultimately turned on their creators, destroying the entire\ncivilization as a result."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "The Royale",
    "Question": "In this episode, how does the landing party eventually end their\nentrapment?",
    "Answer 1": "They buy the casino/hotel, thus\nending the story",
    "Answer 2": "They found a way to\ndisrupt the program",
    "Answer 3": "The formed an alliance with the\ncharacters",
    "Answer 4": "They find a hidden exit",
    "Correct Answer": "They buy the casino/hotel, thus\nending the story",
    "Narrative": "In this episode, the landing party enters a simulation of a hotel/casino through a revolving door. Once inside, they were trapped\nuntil they determined that following the storyline of the book the simulation was based on would conclude the program, thus freeing them."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "Reunion",
    "Question": "In this episode, what did Ambassador K'Ehleyr and Worf mainly have\nin common?",
    "Answer 1": "Their son, Alexander",
    "Answer 2": "They are both Klingon",
    "Answer 3": "They are married to each other",
    "Answer 4": "They both have strong\npersonalities",
    "Correct Answer": "Their son, Alexander",
    "Narrative": "Although they both have strong personalities and they are both Klingon, the main commonality between these two is their son, Alexander."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "Deja Q",
    "Question": "In this episode, what is significant about Q?",
    "Answer 1": "He is no longer omnipotent",
    "Answer 2": "He has lost his memory",
    "Answer 3": "His appearance has been altered",
    "Answer 4": "He has become hyper\nemotional",
    "Correct Answer": "He is no longer omnipotent",
    "Narrative": "In addition to having lost his powers, Q is also completely human, including being mortal. This is particularly distressing to Q, as some\nspecies that he has tormented in the past have learned of this, and seek revenge."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "Jeffrey Combs has played multiple roles in the Star Trek franchise, but\nnever appeared in this series. Which of these actors has?",
    "Answer 1": "Ethan Phillips",
    "Answer 2": "J.G. Hertzler",
    "Answer 3": "John Fleck",
    "Answer 4": "Tim Russ",
    "Correct Answer": "Tim Russ",
    "Narrative": "Tim Russ portrayed Devor in \"Starship Mine\". He also appeared on the bridge of Enterprise-B in \"Tapestry\" as a background character. Of\ncourse he is best known as Tuvok on Voyager."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "Captain's Holiday",
    "Question": "In this episode, what ancient weapon were Picard and Vash looking for?",
    "Answer 1": "Tox Uthat",
    "Answer 2": "Stellum Nox",
    "Answer 3": "Pyroxin Zephyr",
    "Answer 4": "Xithar Vortex",
    "Correct Answer": "Tox Uthat",
    "Narrative": "This weapon was supposed to have the ability to halt nuclear fusion in a star. Imagine what that would do to a civilization."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "Tapestry",
    "Question": "In this episode, Picard is shown to have needed an artifical heart as a\nresult of being impaled by an alien during a game of Dom-Jot? What\nalien species did this?",
    "Answer 1": "Klingon",
    "Answer 2": "Nausicaan",
    "Answer 3": "Tamarian",
    "Answer 4": "Antican",
    "Correct Answer": "Nausicaan",
    "Narrative": "Picard and his friends discovered that the Nausicaans had rigged the table to cheat. Picard, known for his bold and sometimes brash nature\n in his youth, confronted the Nausicaans and got into a fight with them."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "Devil's Due",
    "Question": "In this episode, what species is mentioned to have influenced the \nVentaxians?",
    "Answer 1": "Klingons",
    "Answer 2": "Romulans",
    "Answer 3": "Vulcans",
    "Answer 4": "Andorians",
    "Correct Answer": "Klingons",
    "Narrative": "There is a great deal of Klingon influence in this story. It is mentioned that first contact with Ventax II was made by the Klingons 70 years\n previously. Data mentions a legal case involving a Klingon, and Ardra uses a Klingon image to intimidate the Ventaxians."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "The Host",
    "Question": "What species, to later appear in Deep Space Nine, was the symbiot\nin this episode?",
    "Answer 1": "Trill",
    "Answer 2": "Organian",
    "Answer 3": "Angosian",
    "Answer 4": "Tamarian",
    "Correct Answer": "Trill",
    "Narrative": "The Trill species will return in the characters of Ezri and Jadzia Dax and others in later series."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "In which episode of this series did Thomas Riker first appear?",
    "Answer 1": "The Best of Both Worlds, Part I",
    "Answer 2": "The Inner Light",
    "Answer 3": "Second Chances",
    "Answer 4": "The Outcast",
    "Correct Answer": "Second Chances",
    "Narrative": "Thomas Riker, created as a duplicate of William Riker as a result of a transporter accident first appeared in this episode."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "Technology",
    "Question": "In the episode \"New Ground\", what method of propulsion was \nintroduced?",
    "Answer 1": "Soliton wave",
    "Answer 2": "Quantum torpedo",
    "Answer 3": "Transwarp conduit",
    "Answer 4": "Dyson sphere",
    "Correct Answer": "Soliton wave",
    "Narrative": "The soliton wave generator on a planet would create a powerful, stable wave in subspace. This wave would then be used to propel a starship at \nfaster-than-light speeds without the need for a warp drive on the ship itself. Ultimately, it failed."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "A Fistful of Datas",
    "Question": "In this episode, Worf and Alexander play what role in the simulation?",
    "Answer 1": "Lawmen",
    "Answer 2": "Cowboys",
    "Answer 3": "Outlaws",
    "Answer 4": "Bartenders",
    "Correct Answer": "Lawmen",
    "Narrative": "Alexander, being a fan of Westerns, eagerly immerses himself in the role of the sheriff's deputy, while Worf reluctantly takes on the role\n of the sheriff."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "In the episode \"Relics\", what TOS character was featured?",
    "Answer 1": "Scotty",
    "Answer 2": "Chekov",
    "Answer 3": "Doctor McCoy",
    "Answer 4": "Spock",
    "Correct Answer": "Scotty",
    "Narrative": "The Enterprise stumbles upon a Dyson sphere, with a ship crashed on the outer surface. An away team finds some systems still powered up\n and the chief engineer from the old Enterprise, Montgomery Scott, locked in the transporter cycle."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "A Fistful of Datas",
    "Question": "In this episode, what primary role does Data play in the simulation?",
    "Answer 1": "Frank Hollander",
    "Answer 2": "Hank Frolander",
    "Answer 3": "John Carpenter",
    "Answer 4": "Mark Target",
    "Correct Answer": "Frank Hollander",
    "Narrative": "Data appears in the simulation in multiple rolls, including a prisoner named Eli Hollander, who is Frank's son. Funny note, as the simulation\nprogresses, Data himself starts speaking with a southern drawl."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "Chain of Command, Parts I and II",
    "Question": "In this episode, Picard is captured by the Cardassians and is tortured by\nhis interrogator, Gul Madred. Madred asks Picard how many lights he\nsees. What is Picard's reply.",
    "Answer 1": "There are four lights",
    "Answer 2": "There are five lights",
    "Answer 3": "There are two lights",
    "Answer 4": "There are twenty lights",
    "Correct Answer": "There are four lights",
    "Narrative": "There are actually four lights, but Madred insists there are five, and wants Picard to break by answering that there are five lights. Picard never\ngives in, no matter how long this torture persists."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "Unlike Kirk in TOS, Picard is not often thought of as a \"ladies man\". But\nhe did have several love interests over the course of the series. Of the\nfollowing pairs, which were love interests of Picard?",
    "Answer 1": "Vash and Daren",
    "Answer 2": "Keiko O'Brien and Dr. Ogawa",
    "Answer 3": "Dr. Leah Brahms and  Commander\nShelby",
    "Answer 4": "Ro Laren and Guinan",
    "Correct Answer": "Vash and Daren",
    "Narrative": "Vash and Daren were both love interests of Captain Picard over the course of the series. Although Daren only appeared in a single episode,\nVash made several appearances."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "Inheritance",
    "Question": "In this episode, Data discovers his \"Mother\" on the planet Atrea IV. What\nwas her name?",
    "Answer 1": "Dr. Juliana Tainer",
    "Answer 2": "Dr. Leah Brahms",
    "Answer 3": "Dr. Beverly Crusher",
    "Answer 4": "Dr. Kahn Noonien Soong",
    "Correct Answer": "Dr. Juliana Tainer",
    "Narrative": "It turns out that Dr. Tainer is also an android, but believes she is human. She was constructed by Dr. Noonien Soong, who was also responsible\n for creating Data and Lore. She was constructed to believe she was human and was given the memories and personality of Soong's real \nwife, Juliana O'Donnell."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Next Generation",
    "Description": "Masks",
    "Question": "How many characters did Brent Spiner portray in this episode?",
    "Answer 1": "Five",
    "Answer 2": "Four",
    "Answer 3": "Three",
    "Answer 4": "Six",
    "Correct Answer": "Five",
    "Narrative": "Spiner portrayed five characters in all, including Data. Investigating a rogue comet that's been traveling throughout the universe for over\n 87 million years, Picard discovers alien beings within the comet, which infest the computer systems on the Enterprise, as well as Data."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Animated Series",
    "Description": "Production",
    "Question": "Walter Koenig did not appear in this series. But he is credited with writing\nan episode. Which episode did he write?",
    "Answer 1": "The Infinite Vulcan",
    "Answer 2": "Beyond the Farthest Star",
    "Answer 3": "The Survivor",
    "Answer 4": "The Practical Joker",
    "Correct Answer": "The Infinite Vulcan",
    "Narrative": "Koenig wrote this episode, becoming the first Star Trek actor to write an episode. He was not hired to portray Chekov due to\nbudget limitations."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Animated Series",
    "Description": "The Eye of the Beholder",
    "Question": "The landing party encounters slug-like creatures that Spock believes\nhave what ability?",
    "Answer 1": "Telepathic",
    "Answer 2": "Telekinetic",
    "Answer 3": "Empathic",
    "Answer 4": "Uncanny stength",
    "Correct Answer": "Telepathic",
    "Narrative": "Spock believes that these slug-like creatures have telepathic abilities, but process their thoughts at a speed too fast to comprehend."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Animated Series",
    "Description": "Aliens",
    "Question": "In this series, as a child, what did Spock have as a pet?",
    "Answer 1": "Sehlat",
    "Answer 2": "Targ",
    "Answer 3": "Lycanthan tarantula",
    "Answer 4": "Tribble",
    "Correct Answer": "Sehlat",
    "Narrative": "As a child, Spock had a pet Sehlat named I-Chaya. In the episode \"The Infinite Vulcan\", Unfortunately, I-Chaya died in this episode."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Animated Series",
    "Description": "The Slaver Weapon",
    "Question": "What cat-like creature was introduced in this episode?",
    "Answer 1": "Kzinti",
    "Answer 2": "Vendorian",
    "Answer 3": "Phylosians",
    "Answer 4": "Vendorians",
    "Correct Answer": "Kzinti",
    "Narrative": "The Kzinti are known for their aggressive and warlike nature. They have a hierarchical society with a strong emphasis on military\n prowess and conquest."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Animated Series",
    "Description": "The Jihad",
    "Question": "What artifact were the crew of the Enterprise seeking in this episode?",
    "Answer 1": "Soul of the Skorr",
    "Answer 2": "Tox Uhtat",
    "Answer 3": "Omega molecule",
    "Answer 4": "The Pagh'tem'far",
    "Correct Answer": "Soul of the Skorr",
    "Narrative": "The artifact was a highly sacred and revered relic for the Skorr, a bird-like warrior species. It is a symbol of great religious and cultural \nsignificance to the Skorr, embodying their spiritual essence and unity."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Animated Series",
    "Description": "The Practical Joker",
    "Question": "In this episode, a holodeck was depicted. The first time in the franchise.\nWhat other name was this known by?",
    "Answer 1": "Recreation deck",
    "Answer 2": "Holosuite",
    "Answer 3": "Reality simulator",
    "Answer 4": "Virtual environment room",
    "Correct Answer": "Recreation deck",
    "Narrative": "Some consider this as the prototype of the Holodeck used in Star Trek: The Next Generation, Star Trek: Deep Space Nine, and\n Star Trek: Voyager. In Deep Space Nine, it was known as a Holosuite, which Quark owned. It was housed in Quark's bar."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Animated Series",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "Bem was an unusual alien with certain physical traits? Which of the\nfollowing traits did Bem posses?",
    "Answer 1": "He had a segmented body and\neach segment was detachable",
    "Answer 2": "He could camouflage himself",
    "Answer 3": "Bio luminesence",
    "Answer 4": "He could fly",
    "Correct Answer": "He had a segmented body and\neach segment was detachable",
    "Narrative": "Bem was a member of the Pandorian species."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Deep Space Nine",
    "Description": "Captive Pursuit",
    "Question": "What alien species was featured as \"prey\" in this episode?",
    "Answer 1": "Tosk",
    "Answer 2": "Species 8472",
    "Answer 3": "Tamarians",
    "Answer 4": "Tribbles",
    "Correct Answer": "Tosk",
    "Narrative": "Tosk was a prey species from birth, and was revered on his home planet for not being captured. When the hunters caught up to him on\nthe space station, he was humilated. But O'Brien helped him to escape, thus saving Tosk's reputation."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Deep Space Nine",
    "Description": "Move Along Home",
    "Question": "When the Wadi caught Quark cheating at the game they introduced, they\nforced several crew members into a simulation of the game. What was\nthis game called?",
    "Answer 1": "Chula",
    "Answer 2": "Wakanda",
    "Answer 3": "Balatak",
    "Answer 4": "Fongdi",
    "Correct Answer": "Chula",
    "Narrative": "The Wadi was the first species to make first contact from the Gamma quadrant, and a good impression would be a good start. Unfortunaty,\nthey kept winning at the game they introduced in Quarks bar, and Quark saw no other solution than to cheat. Bad idea."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Deep Space Nine",
    "Description": "The Storyteller",
    "Question": "Chief O'Brien was drafted to be the Bajoran village's storyteller when the\nvillage leader fell ill. He was tasked with saving the village from what\ndreaded entity?",
    "Answer 1": "Dal'Rok",
    "Answer 2": "Kal'Drek",
    "Answer 3": "Mal'Drak",
    "Answer 4": "Jal'Rohk",
    "Correct Answer": "Dal'Rok",
    "Narrative": "The village leader's apprentice was supposed to take over when needed, but the village leader didn't think he was prepared, so he\ndrafted O'Brien. Fortunately, this was just what was needed to get the apprentice sufficiently ready to address the problem."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Deep Space Nine",
    "Description": "Rules of Acquisition",
    "Question": "In this episode, what is the name of the female Ferengi who falls for\nQuark?",
    "Answer 1": "Pel",
    "Answer 2": "Adele",
    "Answer 3": "Prekel",
    "Answer 4": "Gelder",
    "Correct Answer": "Pel",
    "Narrative": "Pel, being a female Ferengi, wasn't allowed to accumulate profit, according to Ferengi law, so she disguised herself as a male. As luck\nwould have it, she fell in love with Quark, which caused quite a problem for all involved once she was discovered."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Deep Space Nine",
    "Description": "The House of Quark",
    "Question": "In this episode, Quark takes credit for the death of a drunk Klingon. The\nKlingon's widow arrives on DS9 and forces him to marry her. What is\nthe name of the Klingon widow?",
    "Answer 1": "Grilka",
    "Answer 2": "R'Vakta",
    "Answer 3": "L'Grath",
    "Answer 4": "K'Lara",
    "Correct Answer": "Grilka",
    "Narrative": "In order for Grilka to save the House of Kozak, she needed to marry Quark."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Deep Space Nine",
    "Description": "Meridian",
    "Question": "In this episode, Jadzia falls in love with an inhabitant of the planet. The\nplanet periodically \"phases\", and disappears from normal space. Who\ndid she fall in love with?",
    "Answer 1": "Deral",
    "Answer 2": "Terak",
    "Answer 3": "Seran",
    "Answer 4": "Merak",
    "Correct Answer": "Deral",
    "Narrative": "Jadzia decides to stay with Deral on the planet when it phases. However, something goes wrong, and the planet can't phase, causing\nthe crew in the runabout to save Jadzia, allowing the planet to phase normally."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Deep Space Nine",
    "Description": "Technology",
    "Question": "Which of the following is true about runabouts, but not shuttlecraft?",
    "Answer 1": "They have their own registry\nnumber",
    "Answer 2": "They are smaller than a\nshuttlecraft",
    "Answer 3": "They are not assigned to a starship\nor space station",
    "Answer 4": "They are less armed than\na shuttlecraft",
    "Correct Answer": "They have their own registry\nnumber",
    "Narrative": "Runabouts are larger and have more defensive capabilities than a shuttlecraft. They are typically assigned to a starshp or space station, and\nthey have their own unique registry number. For example, the Rio Grande's registry was NCC 72452."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Deep Space Nine",
    "Description": "Technology",
    "Question": "As a result of the Dominion threat, how many photon torpedos were\navailable on DS9?",
    "Answer 1": "1,000",
    "Answer 2": "5,000",
    "Answer 3": "2,000",
    "Answer 4": "2,500",
    "Correct Answer": "5,000",
    "Narrative": "It may seem like overkill, but the threat from the Dominion was real, and with the Cardassians added to their alliance, it doesn't seem like\n5,000 photon torpedos was too many."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Deep Space Nine",
    "Description": "Technology",
    "Question": "What was the purpose of Terok Nor prior to the Federation's occupation\nof the space station?",
    "Answer 1": "A prison",
    "Answer 2": "A weapons platform",
    "Answer 3": "A space hotel",
    "Answer 4": "Uridium ore refining facility",
    "Correct Answer": "Uridium ore refining facility",
    "Narrative": "Although it could be said that the station was a prison for Bajorans captured in the war between Cardassia and Bajor, its primary purpose was\nan ore refinery."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Deep Space Nine",
    "Description": "The Emmisary",
    "Question": "In this episode we learn that the name of the Bajoran Wormhole is known\nin Bajoran religious context as what?",
    "Answer 1": "The Celestial Temple",
    "Answer 2": "The Divine Conduit",
    "Answer 3": "The Sacred Portal",
    "Answer 4": "The Holy Passage",
    "Correct Answer": "The Celestial Temple",
    "Narrative": "The wormhole is one of few known \"stable\" wormholes, with one end in the Alpha quadrant, and the other in the Gamma quadrant. It is also the\nhome of the \"Prophets\", non-corporeal beings that are the source of the Bajoran religion."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Deep Space Nine",
    "Description": "Technology",
    "Question": "What illegal technology does the Defiant have as a result of an agreement\nbetween the Federation and the Romulans?",
    "Answer 1": "Cloaking technology",
    "Answer 2": "Subspace warheads",
    "Answer 3": "Polaron beam weapons",
    "Answer 4": "Tri-cobalt device",
    "Correct Answer": "Cloaking technology",
    "Narrative": "As a result of a treaty with the Romulans, the Federation agreed not to develop or implement cloaking technology. However, due to the Dominion\nthreat, an exception was made and the Defiant was fitted with a cloaking device."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Deep Space Nine",
    "Description": "Improbable Cause",
    "Question": "In this first of two parts episode, an explosion occurs in what part of\nthe space station?",
    "Answer 1": "Quark's Bar",
    "Answer 2": "Garak's tailor shop",
    "Answer 3": "Odo's office",
    "Answer 4": "The infirmary",
    "Correct Answer": "Garak's tailor shop",
    "Narrative": "Odo immediately begins an investigation to determine the reason for this apparent attempt on Garak's life. However, Garak doesn't seem \ninterested in cooperating. Odd, isn't it?"
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Deep Space Nine",
    "Description": "Technology",
    "Question": "The Jem'Hadar are intentionally addicted to a drug created by the\nChangelings to ensure loyalty. What is this drug called?",
    "Answer 1": "Ketracel White",
    "Answer 2": "Ketracel Blue",
    "Answer 3": "Synthaclear",
    "Answer 4": "Viroflux",
    "Correct Answer": "Ketracel White",
    "Narrative": "The Jem'Hadar are a warrior species created by the Changelings. They are loyal to the Changelings, but likely only because of the\nKetracel White, which has terrible consequences when not taken regularly."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Deep Space Nine",
    "Description": "Technology",
    "Question": "Vorta are the administrators for the Changelings. When a replacement\nis needed for a Vorta, how is it replaced?",
    "Answer 1": "Cloning",
    "Answer 2": "Neural transfer",
    "Answer 3": "Nanite reconstruction",
    "Answer 4": "Bio-synthesis",
    "Correct Answer": "Cloning",
    "Narrative": "Vorta believe they were  once small ape-like creatures that, as a result of saving a changeling from \"solids\" were given the gift of becoming\nimportant humanoid status."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Deep Space Nine",
    "Description": "Body parts",
    "Question": "In this episode, Quark believes he is going to die. What does he do\nas a result?",
    "Answer 1": "He decides to sell his remains",
    "Answer 2": "He signs over ownership of\nhis bar to Rom",
    "Answer 3": "He commits suicide",
    "Answer 4": "He signs over ownership of\nhis bar to Morn",
    "Correct Answer": "He decides to sell his remains",
    "Narrative": "Obviously, Quark didn't die. But he might wish he did, considering the consequences of finding out he is not going to die after all."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Deep Space Nine",
    "Description": "Far Beyond the Stars",
    "Question": "In this episode, Sisko has visions of another life as an under-appreciated\nwriter in Earth's past. What magazine did he write for?",
    "Answer 1": "Incredible Tales",
    "Answer 2": "The Unbelievable",
    "Answer 3": "Believe",
    "Answer 4": "Twilight Tales",
    "Correct Answer": "Incredible Tales",
    "Narrative": "In this, one of the most well received episodes of the series, Sisko writes a story that is incredibly similar to his real life on DS9. But, in a time when\npeople of color are still discriminated against, he finds it impossible to get his story published."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Deep Space Nine",
    "Description": "In the Pale Moonlight",
    "Question": "In this episode, Sisko conspires to violate Federation regulations in order\nto bring the Romulans into the Dominion war. Who does he conspire\nwith?",
    "Answer 1": "Garak",
    "Answer 2": "Odo",
    "Answer 3": "Major Kira",
    "Answer 4": "Chief O'Brien",
    "Correct Answer": "Garak",
    "Narrative": "The Romulans believe that remaining neutral in the Dominion war is in their best interest. So Sisko conspires to convince the Romulans that\nthe Dominion intends on attacking them. This ploy certainly doesn't portray the Federation in the best light."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Deep Space Nine",
    "Description": "The Begotten",
    "Question": "What Bajoran discovered Odo and performed cruel experiments on him?",
    "Answer 1": "Dr. Mora",
    "Answer 2": "Kira Nerys",
    "Answer 3": "Kai Opaka",
    "Answer 4": "Kai Winn",
    "Correct Answer": "Dr. Mora",
    "Narrative": "Dr. Mora, Odo's \"father\", discovered Odo as an infant, and performed many experiments, some cruiel and painful, to get the gelatinous form\nto respond."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Voyager",
    "Description": "Meld",
    "Question": "In this episode, Tuvok mind-melds with a crewman who has confessed to\nmurdering another crew. Who did Tuvok mind-meld with?",
    "Answer 1": "Lon Suder",
    "Answer 2": "B'elanna Torres",
    "Answer 3": "Neelix",
    "Answer 4": "Tom Paris",
    "Correct Answer": "Lon Suder",
    "Narrative": "Suder, who murdered another crewman, allowed Tuvok to mind-meld with him in an attempt to calm his chaotic thoughts and urges. In the\nprocess, Tuvok nearly loses himself to Suder's thoughts."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Voyager",
    "Description": "False Profits",
    "Question": "In this episode, Neelix pretends to be a Ferengi in an attempt to fool the\nFerengi who are defauding the inhabitants of a bronze age planet. Who\ndoes Neelix claim to be?",
    "Answer 1": "Grand Proxy",
    "Answer 2": "Celestial Banker",
    "Answer 3": "Grand Inquisitor",
    "Answer 4": "Master Collector",
    "Correct Answer": "Grand Proxy",
    "Narrative": "Voyager comes across a pair of Alpha Quadrant Ferengis who have set themselves up as gods on a primitive planet. Voyager wants to end their reign and use the nearby\n wormhole to return home."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Voyager",
    "Description": "The Q and the Grey",
    "Question": "In this episode, what relationship does Q want to have with Janeway?",
    "Answer 1": "His mate",
    "Answer 2": "His partner",
    "Answer 3": "His proxy",
    "Answer 4": "His wife",
    "Correct Answer": "His mate",
    "Narrative": "Civil war has erupted in the Q Continuum, and for some reason, Q believes that a Q child will restore balance. Seems fishy to  me."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Voyager",
    "Description": "Real Life",
    "Question": "In this episode, the holographic doctor creates a family for himself in the\nholodeck. What about this family did Torres change to make it more\nrealistic?",
    "Answer 1": "Parental disagreements",
    "Answer 2": "Extended family problems",
    "Answer 3": "Child rebellion",
    "Answer 4": "Balancing work and famly",
    "Correct Answer": "Child rebellion",
    "Narrative": "The doctor's \"son\", became friends with a Klingon teenager who exhibited behaviors that the doctor did not want his\nson to learn from him."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Voyager",
    "Description": "Technology",
    "Question": "Voyager was an advanced starship that had several new features. Which\nof these did Voyager have that were not typical of previous starships?",
    "Answer 1": "Bio-neural gelpacks",
    "Answer 2": "Ablative hull armor",
    "Answer 3": "Quantum torpedos",
    "Answer 4": "Multi-phasic shielding",
    "Correct Answer": "Bio-neural gelpacks",
    "Narrative": "The packs had both mechanical and biological components, and contained bio-neural cells and neurodes which organized \ninformation more efficiently and faster than isolinear circuitry."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Voyager",
    "Description": "Scorpion, Part I",
    "Question": "In this episode, what famous historical figure did Captain Janeway have\na conversation with?",
    "Answer 1": "Galileo Galilei",
    "Answer 2": "Leonardo Da Vinci",
    "Answer 3": "Stephen Hawking",
    "Answer 4": "Albert Einstein",
    "Correct Answer": "Leonardo Da Vinci",
    "Narrative": "Janeway turns to her Leonardo da Vinci holodeck program for inspiration and devises a risky plan to book safe passage through Borg\n space by working together with the Borg to defeat Species 8472."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Voyager",
    "Description": "Scorpion, Part II",
    "Question": "What does Captain Janeway hope to get from the Borg by providing\ntechnology to them that will defeat Species 8472?",
    "Answer 1": "Free passage through Borg\nspace",
    "Answer 2": "A transwarp conduit",
    "Answer 3": "A veniculum",
    "Answer 4": "A Borg data module",
    "Correct Answer": "Free passage through Borg\nspace",
    "Narrative": "The holographic doctor deviced nano-technology that would defeat Species 8472. Janeway offered an alliance with the Borg that would provide\nthe Borg with the technology \"after\" they were out of Borg space."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Voyager",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "Seven of Nine became part of Voyager's crew in what episode?",
    "Answer 1": "Scorpion",
    "Answer 2": "Year of Hell",
    "Answer 3": "Equinox",
    "Answer 4": "Unimatrix zero",
    "Correct Answer": "Scorpion",
    "Narrative": "As a result of Species 8472 destroying her Borg Cube, Seven of Nine was transported along with the away team to Voyager, where\nshe became a permanent member of Voyager's crew."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Voyager",
    "Description": "Live Fast and Prosper",
    "Question": "Which Voyager crew were being portrayed by imposters in this\nepisode?",
    "Answer 1": "Janeway, Neelix and Seven",
    "Answer 2": "Janeway, Tuvok and Chakotay",
    "Answer 3": "Janeway, Seven and Kes",
    "Answer 4": "Janeway, Tuvok and Kim",
    "Correct Answer": "Janeway, Tuvok and Chakotay",
    "Narrative": "This was a case of identify theft in order to profit from the good name of Voyager and crew."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Voyager",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "What are the names of the two main characters in Naomi Wildman's\nholodeck simulation?",
    "Answer 1": "Flotter and Trevis",
    "Answer 2": "Spark and Ashy",
    "Answer 3": "Floater and Tree",
    "Answer 4": "Sandy and Cactus",
    "Correct Answer": "Flotter and Trevis",
    "Narrative": "Neelix and Naomi chose this chapter to play out in USS Voyager's holodeck after eliminating two other possible choices. When she picked out the story, he initially\n cautioned her, saying it sounded a little scary. She reassured him that she wouldn't be scared if he was with her."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Voyager",
    "Description": "Blink of an Eye",
    "Question": "In this episode, what did the inhabitants of the planet call Voyager?",
    "Answer 1": "Sky Ship",
    "Answer 2": "Star Ship",
    "Answer 3": "Eye in the Sky",
    "Answer 4": "New Star",
    "Correct Answer": "Sky Ship",
    "Narrative": "Voyager becomes locked in orbit of a planet on which times passes much faster than on Voyager. This causes tectonic issues on the planet that\nthreatens the planet. Eventually, the inhabitants reach a level of technology that allows them to free Voyager."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Voyager",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "Jason Alexander (known from Seinfeld) appeared in which episode?",
    "Answer 1": "Think Tank",
    "Answer 2": "Equinox",
    "Answer 3": "Spirit Folk",
    "Answer 4": "The 37's",
    "Correct Answer": "Think Tank",
    "Narrative": "Kurros was the spokesperson of the \"Think Tank\", a diverse group of alien scholars who traveled about the galaxy, offering to solve\n people's problems for a price."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Voyager",
    "Description": "Technology",
    "Question": "Which of the following was a new feature for starships, unique to\nVoyager at the time?",
    "Answer 1": "Variable Geometry Warp\n Nacelles",
    "Answer 2": "Ablative hull armor",
    "Answer 3": "Multi-phasic shielding",
    "Answer 4": "Photon torpedos",
    "Correct Answer": "Variable Geometry Warp\n Nacelles",
    "Narrative": "The nacelles were \"raised\" for warp speed, and \"lowered\" for sub-light speed. There is no specific information to describe why this was\nnecessary or desirable, but there is speculation that this lessened the impact of warp fields on inhabited planets."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Enterprise",
    "Description": "Technology",
    "Question": "If this series was picked up for a 5th season, what upgrade would\nNX-01 Enterprise have received?",
    "Answer 1": "A new hull",
    "Answer 2": "Shields",
    "Answer 3": "Photon torpedos",
    "Answer 4": "Tractor beam",
    "Correct Answer": "A new hull",
    "Narrative": "We'll never know for sure, because Enterprise was not renewed for a 5th season. But the hull was planned to be an \"outer\" hull that would\nhave made NX-01 more resemble NCC-1701."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Enterprise",
    "Description": "Aliens",
    "Question": "What species built a weapon that was created to destroy Earth?",
    "Answer 1": "Xindi",
    "Answer 2": "Suliban",
    "Answer 3": "Klingons",
    "Answer 4": "Romulans",
    "Correct Answer": "Xindi",
    "Narrative": "The Xindi, falsely believing that humans would destroy their homeworld if they did not strike first, created a weapon designed to destroy Earth.\nFortunately, the lie was seen through and the Xindi did not destroy Earth."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Enterprise",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "What crewman was \"Sim\" a clone of?",
    "Answer 1": "Captain Archer",
    "Answer 2": "Trip Tucker",
    "Answer 3": "Doctor Phlox",
    "Answer 4": "T'Pol",
    "Correct Answer": "Trip Tucker",
    "Narrative": "Sim was created when Dr. Phlox used a Lyssarian Desert Larvae which has the unique ability to rapidly grow into a genetic duplicate of a human."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Enterprise",
    "Description": "Aquisition",
    "Question": "This episode features a character portraying a Ferengi that was a \nregular in a previous series. Which character?",
    "Answer 1": "Tuvok",
    "Answer 2": "Nog",
    "Answer 3": "Neelix",
    "Answer 4": "Data",
    "Correct Answer": "Neelix",
    "Narrative": "Ethan Phillips, who played Neelix on Star Trek: Voyager, portrayed a Ferengi named Ulis."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Enterprise",
    "Description": "Carbon Creek",
    "Question": "In this episode, T'Pol tells Captain Archer and Trip Tucker a story of an\nalternate Vulcan/Human first contact. When asked if the story was true,\nwhat was T'Pol's reply?",
    "Answer 1": "Yes. It is true.",
    "Answer 2": "No. I made it up.",
    "Answer 3": "You asked me to tell you a story.",
    "Answer 4": "You figure it out",
    "Correct Answer": "You asked me to tell you a story.",
    "Narrative": "In the final scene of the episode, T'Pol opens an old handbag and retrieves a picture of T'Mir and her crewmates, and a piece of velcro, \nindicating that the story was indeed true."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Enterprise",
    "Description": "The Forge",
    "Question": "In this episode, what group is suspected of bombing the Earth\nembassy on Vulcan?",
    "Answer 1": "Syrrannites",
    "Answer 2": "Maquis",
    "Answer 3": "Section 31",
    "Answer 4": "Tal Shiar",
    "Correct Answer": "Syrrannites",
    "Narrative": "Admiral Maxwell Forrest is having a discussion with ambassador Soval in the Earth embassy on Vulcan when a bomb explodes, \nkilling 43 people including Forrest."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Enterprise",
    "Description": "Daedalus",
    "Question": "In this episode, Dr. Emory Erickson arrives onboard Enterprise, \nsupposedly to conduct tests for subquantum transportation. What is his\ntrue mission?",
    "Answer 1": "Save his son",
    "Answer 2": "Kill Captain Archer",
    "Answer 3": "Sabotage the transporters",
    "Answer 4": "Steal Enterprise",
    "Correct Answer": "Save his son",
    "Narrative": "The crew reluctantly follows Erickson's lead as he tries to re-materialize Quinn from a phantom-like state stemming from a transporter\n accident 15 years earlier."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Enterprise",
    "Description": "In a Mirror, Darkly",
    "Question": "In this two part episode, who is revealed to be the emperor?",
    "Answer 1": "Admiral Forrest",
    "Answer 2": "Hoshi Sato",
    "Answer 3": "T'Pol",
    "Answer 4": "Doctor Phlox",
    "Correct Answer": "Hoshi Sato",
    "Narrative": "After gaining control of the Terran Empire's most powerful starship, the USS Defiant, Hoshi declares herself Empress, leveraging the\n advanced technology of the Defiant to seize power."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Enterprise",
    "Description": "In a Mirror, Darkly",
    "Question": "In this two part episode, which ship does the emperor acquire to solidfy\npower?",
    "Answer 1": "Enterprise NCC-1701",
    "Answer 2": "Defiant",
    "Answer 3": "Farragut",
    "Answer 4": "Reliant",
    "Correct Answer": "Defiant",
    "Narrative": "Once the USS Defiant is acquired, Hoshi Sato declares herself Empress."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Enterprise",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "What type of dog did Captain Archer have onboard NX-01?",
    "Answer 1": "German Shepherd",
    "Answer 2": "Border Collie",
    "Answer 3": "Beagle",
    "Answer 4": "Golden Retriever",
    "Correct Answer": "Beagle",
    "Narrative": "Captain Archer's dog was a Beagle named Porthos, a name from \"The Three Musketeers\" by Alexandre Dumas. In the novel, Porthos is\n one of the three  loyal musketeers serving the French king, alongside Athos and Aramis. The name reflects the loyalty and companionship\n that Archer values  in his canine friend."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Enterprise",
    "Description": "Aliens",
    "Question": "How many species of Xindi still exist in the Entperise NX-01's timeline?",
    "Answer 1": 4,
    "Answer 2": 5,
    "Answer 3": 3,
    "Answer 4": 6,
    "Correct Answer": 5,
    "Narrative": "The Xindi were five distinct species: Primate, Insectoid, Reptilian, Aquatic and Arboreal. A sixth species, Avian, are extinct."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Enterprise",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "Daniels, a time traveler prominent in the Temporal Cold War was from\nwhich century?",
    "Answer 1": "26th",
    "Answer 2": "28th",
    "Answer 3": "27th",
    "Answer 4": "31st",
    "Correct Answer": "31st",
    "Narrative": "Daniels was an operative from the 31st century and a major player in the Temporal Cold War. Daniels had frequent interactions with\n the crew of Enterprise NX-01 in the 2150s and often assisted them in preventing temporal incursions by various factions in the Cold War."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Strange New Worlds",
    "Description": "Actor",
    "Question": "In this series, Spock is portrayed by the grandson of a famous actor of\nthe 1940's to the 1960's. Who is Spock's grandfather?",
    "Answer 1": "Austin Peck",
    "Answer 2": "Gregory Peck",
    "Answer 3": "Andrew Peck",
    "Answer 4": "Stephen Peck",
    "Correct Answer": "Gregory Peck",
    "Narrative": "Gregory Peck, the famous actor from the 1940's to the 1960's is the grandfather of Spock (Ethan Peck)."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Strange New Worlds",
    "Description": "Regulations",
    "Question": "In the first episode, \"Strange New Worlds\", the crew of the Enterprise were\nfaced with breaking one of the most important regulations in the Federation.\nWhich regulation was it?",
    "Answer 1": "General order number 1",
    "Answer 2": "General order number 7",
    "Answer 3": "General order number 24",
    "Answer 4": "General order number 15",
    "Correct Answer": "General order number 1",
    "Narrative": "Also known as \"The Prime Directive\", this order states that there must be no interference in the normal evolution of a less advanced civilization. General order number 7 states that no vessel may\nvisit Talos IV. General order number 15 states that no flag officer (Admiral) may beam into a hazardous area without an armed escort. General order number 24 provides authorization to destroy \nall life on a planet."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Strange New Worlds",
    "Description": "Memento Mori",
    "Question": "In this episode the Enterprise encountered a known and very dangerious\nspecies. Which species?",
    "Answer 1": "Species 8472",
    "Answer 2": "The Borg",
    "Answer 3": "Klingons",
    "Answer 4": "Gorn",
    "Correct Answer": "Gorn",
    "Narrative": "The Gorn, last seen in The Original Series, has gone through a major metamorphosis. They hunt (and eat) other species, including humans."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Strange New Worlds",
    "Description": "Subspace Rhapsody",
    "Question": "In this unusual episode, the crew of the Enterprise (and other species\nwithin range, broke out into song and dance. What caused this?",
    "Answer 1": "Quantum probability field",
    "Answer 2": "Subspace harmonics anomoly",
    "Answer 3": "A warp core explosion",
    "Answer 4": "A transporter malfunction",
    "Correct Answer": "Quantum probability field",
    "Narrative": "This experimental field got a little out of control and caused any ship's crew within range to break out into song and dance, during which some information would be\nexposed that was to remain confidential. Not good, right?"
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Strange New Worlds",
    "Description": "Those Old Scientists",
    "Question": "In this episode, two characters from \"Lower Decks\" were transported to \nthe timeline and location of the Entperise from SNW. Which characters?",
    "Answer 1": "Mariner and Rutherford",
    "Answer 2": "Mariner and Ransom",
    "Answer 3": "Ransom and Rutherford",
    "Answer 4": "Mariner and Boimler",
    "Correct Answer": "Mariner and Boimler",
    "Narrative": "An accident while investigating a time portal sends Ensigns Beckett Mariner and Bradward Boimler through time from the 24th Century, and Captain Pike and his crew must get them back \nwhere they belong before they can alter the timeline."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Strange New Worlds",
    "Description": "Actor",
    "Question": "Hemmer, the chief engineer of the Enterprise is a member of what species?",
    "Answer 1": "Andorian",
    "Answer 2": "Aenar",
    "Answer 3": "Vulcan",
    "Answer 4": "Romulan",
    "Correct Answer": "Aenar",
    "Narrative": "Hemmer portrays a blind Aenar who manages quite well in his job despite his disability. He befriends the young cadet Uhura, and with his advise, she decides to stick with Starfleet, despite\nher reservations as to whether she \"belongs\"."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Strange New Worlds",
    "Description": "Actor",
    "Question": "Babs Olusanmokun, who portrays Dr. M'Benga is Nigerian. In reality, what\nnationality is Babs?",
    "Answer 1": "Kenyan",
    "Answer 2": "Ugandan",
    "Answer 3": "South African",
    "Answer 4": "Egyptian",
    "Correct Answer": "Kenyan",
    "Narrative": "Similarly, the New York-born Celia Rose Gooding plays Uhura, who was established as having been born in Kenya."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Strange New Worlds",
    "Description": "Actor",
    "Question": "Anson Mount who portrays Captain Pike was notably missing for much of\nthe first three episodes of season 2. Why?",
    "Answer 1": "He was injured on set",
    "Answer 2": "He took paternity leave",
    "Answer 3": "He had Covid",
    "Answer 4": "His mother died",
    "Correct Answer": "He took paternity leave",
    "Narrative": "Yes, Anson Mount's (Pike) wife just had a baby, and Mount was taking paternity leave to be with his wife and new child."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Strange New Worlds",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "Who portrayed the character Commander Buck Martinez in the episode\nThose Old Scientists?",
    "Answer 1": "Ron Howard",
    "Answer 2": "Jack Quaid",
    "Answer 3": "Clint Howard",
    "Answer 4": "Randy Quaid",
    "Correct Answer": "Clint Howard",
    "Narrative": "Yes, it was Balok himself (obviously much older in this episode). Tranya anyone???"
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Strange New Worlds",
    "Description": "Episode",
    "Question": "In which episode of this series was a memorial presented for Uhura \n(Nichelle Nicoles)?",
    "Answer 1": "Hegemony",
    "Answer 2": "Broken Circle",
    "Answer 3": "Subspace Rhapsody",
    "Answer 4": "Lost in Translation",
    "Correct Answer": "Broken Circle",
    "Narrative": "Includes an in memoriam message for Nichelle Nichols, who played Uhura in the original Star Trek (1966) series and movies and who passed away on July 22, 2022 at the age of 89."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Motion Picture",
    "Description": "Quotes",
    "Question": "William Shatner thought that this film was a flop after seeing it on the\nbig screen for the first time. What was his reply when asked about it\n15 years later?",
    "Answer 1": "I stand by my original statement",
    "Answer 2": "Shows you what I know",
    "Answer 3": "It wasn't so bad",
    "Answer 4": "I still think it was crap",
    "Correct Answer": "Shows you what I know",
    "Narrative": "Shatner, who saw the completed film for the first time at the world premiere, was struck by the overall sluggishness of this film, and was convinced\n that the Star Trek franchise died there and then. He opined, \"Well, that's it. We gave it our best shot, it wasn't good, and it will never happen again."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Motion Picture",
    "Description": "Uniforms",
    "Question": "Which actor stated that they didn't like the uniforms worn in this film\n because they were unisex and too drab?",
    "Answer 1": "Nichelle Nichols",
    "Answer 2": "James Doohan",
    "Answer 3": "William Shatner",
    "Answer 4": "Grace Lee Whitney",
    "Correct Answer": "Nichelle Nichols",
    "Narrative": "Nichols noted in her autobiography that she was one of the actresses most opposed to the new uniforms added for this film."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Motion Picture",
    "Description": "Lawsuits",
    "Question": "Which actor agreed to appear in this film only after the studio agreed to\na settlement for using his likeness in advertising without permission?",
    "Answer 1": "William Shatner",
    "Answer 2": "Leonard Nimoy",
    "Answer 3": "George Takei",
    "Answer 4": "Walter Koenig",
    "Correct Answer": "Leonard Nimoy",
    "Narrative": "Henry Fonda told Nimoy that he hoped he (Nimoy) would receive a lot of money for all those ads. Nimoy was completely unaware that his\n likeness as Spock was being used in Heineken beer advertisements, including billboards and a now famous commercial."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Motion Picture",
    "Description": "Theme music",
    "Question": "This film's theme was so liked by Gene Roddenberry, that it was used \nagain in which future productions?",
    "Answer 1": "The Next Generation and The\nFinal Frontier",
    "Answer 2": "Voyager and The Wrath of\nKhan",
    "Answer 3": "Deep Space Nine and The Voyage\nHome",
    "Answer 4": "Enterprise and First\nContact",
    "Correct Answer": "The Next Generation and The\nFinal Frontier",
    "Narrative": "Roddenberry so loved the main theme from the score that he reused this for Star Trek: The Next Generation (1987). This was also reused in\n Star Trek V: The Final Frontier (1989), after not being used in the second, third and fourth films."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Motion Picture",
    "Description": "Cast extras",
    "Question": "Which main cast member's twin sons were cast as extras in this film?",
    "Answer 1": "William Shatner",
    "Answer 2": "Leonard Nimoy",
    "Answer 3": "James Doohan",
    "Answer 4": "DeForest Kelley",
    "Correct Answer": "James Doohan",
    "Narrative": "Doohan's twin sons, Montgomery Doohan and Christopher Doohan, appear as extras in this film."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Motion Picture",
    "Description": "Uniforms",
    "Question": "The uniforms worn in this film were re-used in which future film or\ntelevision series?",
    "Answer 1": "The Wrath of Khan",
    "Answer 2": "Voyager",
    "Answer 3": "The Search for Spock",
    "Answer 4": "They were never worn\nagain.",
    "Correct Answer": "They were never worn\nagain.",
    "Narrative": "The uniforms that appear in this film never again appear in any other Star Trek episode or movie. What appears to be a buckle on the uniform\n was intended to be a device that relays medical readings to the medical bay computer."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Motion Picture",
    "Description": "Production",
    "Question": "Which famous science fiction author provided technical consultation for\nthis film?",
    "Answer 1": "Arthur C. Clarke",
    "Answer 2": "Ray Bradbury",
    "Answer 3": "Harlan Ellison",
    "Answer 4": "Isaac Asimov",
    "Correct Answer": "Isaac Asimov",
    "Narrative": "This film also received technical consultation from NASA, the Jet Propulsion Laboratory at California Institute of Technology, and the\n Massachusetts Institute of Technology."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Motion Picture",
    "Description": "Film title",
    "Question": "One of the several derogatory nicknames for this film included what?",
    "Answer 1": "The Motionless Picture",
    "Answer 2": "The No Motion Picture",
    "Answer 3": "The Low Motion Picture",
    "Answer 4": "The Stop Motion Picture",
    "Correct Answer": "The Motionless Picture",
    "Narrative": "Others derogatory names included The Motion Sickness Picture and The Slow Motion Picture."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Motion Picture",
    "Description": "Production",
    "Question": "Where (on Earth) were the scenes of Vulcan filmed?",
    "Answer 1": "Yosemite National Park",
    "Answer 2": "Yellowstone National Park",
    "Answer 3": "Turkey",
    "Answer 4": "Saudi Arabia",
    "Correct Answer": "Yellowstone National Park",
    "Narrative": "Yellowstone was selected for Vulcan after filming in Turkish ruins proved to be too expensive. Securing permission for filming the scenes was difficult in the\n middle of the summer tourist season, but the Parks Department acquiesced so long as the crew remained on the boardwalks to prevent damage to geological formations."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Motion Picture",
    "Description": "Shuttlecraft",
    "Question": "The long-range shuttle carrying Spock has Vulcan lettering on the top\n of the side of the craft, and under this reads...what?",
    "Answer 1": "Vulcan",
    "Answer 2": "Surak",
    "Answer 3": "Kolinar",
    "Answer 4": "Spock's Shuttlecraft",
    "Correct Answer": "Surak",
    "Narrative": "Surak was the founder of Vulcan logic and the idea of suppression of emotions."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Wrath of Khan",
    "Description": "Casting",
    "Question": "After reluctantly being convinced to appear in the first film, Leonard Nimoy\n initially had no interest in a second. Harve Bennett finally convinced\n Nimoy to sign onto the film.What did he offer Nimoy?",
    "Answer 1": "Double his salary",
    "Answer 2": "A death scene",
    "Answer 3": "Triple his salary",
    "Answer 4": "More lines than Kirk",
    "Correct Answer": "A death scene",
    "Narrative": "Presumably to ensure that Nimoy would never be cast again in the franchise. I think we all know how that went."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Wrath of Khan",
    "Description": "Set decoration",
    "Question": "Which of the following items were displayed in Kirk's ready room?",
    "Answer 1": "PET Computer",
    "Answer 2": "Goldfish bowl",
    "Answer 3": "Picture of USS Farragut",
    "Answer 4": "A ship's compass",
    "Correct Answer": "PET Computer",
    "Narrative": "Some of the other items in the ready room included a sextant, a ship's wheel and antique books."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Wrath of Khan",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "Which of the Reliant's crew was a recurring member of the Enterprise\n crew on The Original Series",
    "Answer 1": "Kyle",
    "Answer 2": "Chekov",
    "Answer 3": "Terell",
    "Answer 4": "Beach",
    "Correct Answer": "Kyle",
    "Narrative": "Chekov is a regular crew member, whereas Kyle was a recurring crew member."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Wrath of Khan",
    "Description": "Actor",
    "Question": "Other than Leonard Nimoy, what actor initially declined to return for this\nfilm?",
    "Answer 1": "Walter Koenig",
    "Answer 2": "George Takei",
    "Answer 3": "DeForest Kelley",
    "Answer 4": "James Doohan",
    "Correct Answer": "George Takei",
    "Narrative": "Takei was subsequently convinced to return to reprise his role as Sulu after William Shatner asked him to reconsider."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Wrath of Khan",
    "Description": "Production",
    "Question": "The scenic view of San Francisco through Kirk's apartment window is a\n painting, originally created for which film?",
    "Answer 1": "Dirty Harry",
    "Answer 2": "What's Up Doc",
    "Answer 3": "The Towering Inferno",
    "Answer 4": "Bullitt",
    "Correct Answer": "The Towering Inferno",
    "Narrative": "In front of the backdrop were placed a couple of models of futuristic skyscrapers, with working lights and elevators. Thus, assuming that Kirk's apartment is in the same place as\n the tower in \"The Towering Inferno\", then his address is 655 Market Street, San Francisco, California, on the 135th floor."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Wrath of Khan",
    "Description": "Production",
    "Question": "In this film, how was USS Reliant differentiated from the USS Enterprise?",
    "Answer 1": "The saucer section was larger",
    "Answer 2": "The nacelles were below the\nfuselage",
    "Answer 3": "The Engineering section\n was longer",
    "Answer 4": "There was no difference",
    "Correct Answer": "The nacelles were below the\nfuselage",
    "Narrative": "As the fundamental components of both ships are the same (saucer, nacelles, etc.), this was seen as being an effective way to visually differentiate the two vessels, particularly\n during action sequences when both ships are in the same scene."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Wrath of Khan",
    "Description": "Props",
    "Question": "What was used to make the Ceti Eels used by Khan appear \"slimy\"?",
    "Answer 1": "Motor oil",
    "Answer 2": "Raspberry jelly",
    "Answer 3": "Honey",
    "Answer 4": "Bacon fat",
    "Correct Answer": "Raspberry jelly",
    "Narrative": "The baby Ceti eels were pulled along the actors' cheeks using a piece of string. They were made out of a stretchy rubber, allowing them to seem to crawl along, and covered with\n raspberry jelly to give them a slimy appearance."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Wrath of Khan",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "Marla McGivers from the TOS episode Space Seed did not appear in this\nfilm. The reason given in the film was that she died while in exile.\nWhat killed her?",
    "Answer 1": "Ceti eels",
    "Answer 2": "Prolonged illness",
    "Answer 3": "Dehydration",
    "Answer 4": "Old age",
    "Correct Answer": "Ceti eels",
    "Narrative": "The character of Marla McGivers from Space Seed (1967) was originally intended to reappear in this film, with Madlyn Rhue reprising her role."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Wrath of Khan",
    "Description": "Production",
    "Question": "The Genesis sequence called for a long and massive explosion. Where\nin San Francisco was this filmed?",
    "Answer 1": "Chase Center",
    "Answer 2": "The Cow Palace",
    "Answer 3": "The Fillmore",
    "Answer 4": "Golden Gate Theater",
    "Correct Answer": "The Cow Palace",
    "Narrative": "ILM rented the Cow Palace in San Francisco for the effect. They covered the ceiling with a black cloth and placed the camera on the floor looking up at it. The explosion\n would occur directly above the camera so the fall-out would appear to rush directly towards the point of view."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Wrath of Khan",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "What was unusual about Saavik's name?",
    "Answer 1": "It was longer than usual",
    "Answer 2": "It was shorter than usual",
    "Answer 3": "It began with an \"S",
    "Answer 4": "It was a Romulan name",
    "Correct Answer": "It began with an \"S",
    "Narrative": "Previously, only male Vulcans had names that began with \"S\" (Spock, Sarek, Surak) while female Vulcans had name that began with \"T\" (T'Pau, T'Pring)."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Search for Spock",
    "Description": "Casting",
    "Question": "Leonard Nimoy directed this film and his first choice to play Kruge was\nnot Christopher Lloyd. Who was?",
    "Answer 1": "James Earl Jones",
    "Answer 2": "Sean Connery",
    "Answer 3": "Edward James Olmos",
    "Answer 4": "Harrison Ford",
    "Correct Answer": "Edward James Olmos",
    "Narrative": "Nimoy finally cast Lloyd because he came off more operatic and physically intimidating."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Search for Spock",
    "Description": "Special effects",
    "Question": "When the crew is standing on the bluff supposedly watching the flaming\nEnterprise hulk, they were in fact watching...what?",
    "Answer 1": "A flaming car",
    "Answer 2": "A flaming haystack",
    "Answer 3": "A flaming tennis ball",
    "Answer 4": "A flaming Frisbee",
    "Correct Answer": "A flaming tennis ball",
    "Narrative": "Yep. That's right. They were in fact watching a tennis ball mounted on an overhead boom microphone."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Search for Spock",
    "Description": "Casting",
    "Question": "How many different actors portrayed Spock in this film?",
    "Answer 1": "Four",
    "Answer 2": "Two",
    "Answer 3": "Six",
    "Answer 4": "Three",
    "Correct Answer": "Six",
    "Narrative": "This includes Spock as an adult and five stages of growth after being found on the Genesis planet."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Search for Spock",
    "Description": "Sets",
    "Question": "When beaming down in the transporter room, what sign can be seen\nin the back?",
    "Answer 1": "Capacity 4 crew",
    "Answer 2": "No smoking",
    "Answer 3": "Fasten seat belts",
    "Answer 4": "No food or drink",
    "Correct Answer": "No smoking",
    "Narrative": "Although Gene Roddenberry had this sign removed in another area of the ship, it remained in the transporter room. Roddenberry thought that the use of tobacco\nwould not a a thing of the future."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Search for Spock",
    "Description": "Network broadcast",
    "Question": "This film's broadcast network premiere came slightly earlier than first \nplanned. ABC decided to broadcast the film instead of what?",
    "Answer 1": "Monday Night Football",
    "Answer 2": "E.T.",
    "Answer 3": "The Winds of War",
    "Answer 4": "The Day After",
    "Correct Answer": "Monday Night Football",
    "Narrative": "ABC decided to broadcast the film instead of Monday Night Football during the first week of the 1987 NFL players strike."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Search for Spock",
    "Description": "Aliens",
    "Question": "In this film, during McCoy's bar scene, what alien species could be seen?",
    "Answer 1": "Tribble",
    "Answer 2": "Romulan",
    "Answer 3": "Klingon",
    "Answer 4": "El Aurian",
    "Correct Answer": "Tribble",
    "Narrative": "A popular creature from the episode The Trouble with Tribbles (1967), Tribbles made a cameo appearance during the bar sequence where Dr. McCoy tries to hire a ship."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Search for Spock",
    "Description": "Production",
    "Question": "Paramount apparently had some pretty hefty issues with one member\nof the production staff and barred him from the set. Who?",
    "Answer 1": "Gene Roddenberry",
    "Answer 2": "Leonard Nimoy",
    "Answer 3": "Harve Bennett",
    "Answer 4": "Robert Fletcher",
    "Correct Answer": "Gene Roddenberry",
    "Narrative": "Yep. The big bird himself. After having problems with Roddenberry trying to interfere with production on the first two movies, Paramount Studios had him effectively barred from\n the set during the filming of this movie."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Search for Spock",
    "Description": "Production",
    "Question": "Early on, Paramount toyed with the idea of making this film in 3D. Which\nfilm did they do this with instead?",
    "Answer 1": "Friday the 13th Part III",
    "Answer 2": "Flashdance",
    "Answer 3": "Indiana Jones and the Temple\nof Doom",
    "Answer 4": "The Explorers",
    "Correct Answer": "Friday the 13th Part III",
    "Narrative": "In early 1982, Paramount Studios toyed with the idea of having this film being 3-D. Instead, the studio decided that 3-D was better suited for Friday the 13th: Part 3 (1982)."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Search for Spock",
    "Description": "Actors",
    "Question": "Kirsty Alley did not reprise her role in this film. Why?",
    "Answer 1": "She was afraid of being\ntypecast",
    "Answer 2": "She wasn't available",
    "Answer 3": "She wanted more money",
    "Answer 4": "She wanted more screen\ntime",
    "Correct Answer": "She was afraid of being\ntypecast",
    "Narrative": "Kirstie Alley, who played Saavik in Star Trek II: The Wrath of Khan (1982), did not reprise her role as Saavik because she was afraid of being typecast. Leonard Nimoy had \nbeen looking for an actress to play Saavik after she passed up the role. He met Robin Curtis, who has just arrived in Los Angeles, and hired her the next day."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Lower Decks",
    "Description": "Ships",
    "Question": "The Cerritos is what class ship?",
    "Answer 1": "Ohio class",
    "Answer 2": "California class",
    "Answer 3": "Nevada class",
    "Answer 4": "Montana class",
    "Correct Answer": "California class",
    "Narrative": "The Cerritos has several elements from the Galaxy and Nebula class. It's trimmed in the same mustard-gold colour as the support branch uniforms. Its sister ships\n are trimmed in the colour of their \"specialty\"; the USS Merced, for example, is trimmed in blue, referencing its science-oriented assignment. That helps the audience\n differentiate them on screen."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Lower Decks",
    "Description": "Characters",
    "Question": "Live action versions of two crew from this series appeared in an episode of\nStrange New Worlds. Which two crew?",
    "Answer 1": "Rutherford and Mariner",
    "Answer 2": "Mariner and Shrax",
    "Answer 3": "Boimler and Rutherford",
    "Answer 4": "Mariner and Boimler",
    "Correct Answer": "Mariner and Boimler",
    "Narrative": "Boimler, while waiting for Captain Pike in his ready room, was found by Uhura, sitting on Pike's horse saddle. Probably not a good idea."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Lower Decks",
    "Description": "Ships",
    "Question": "The Cerritos, a California class ship, was originally to be given the name\nof a California city. Which city?",
    "Answer 1": "San Francisco",
    "Answer 2": "San Diego",
    "Answer 3": "Santa Cruz",
    "Answer 4": "San Jose",
    "Correct Answer": "San Diego",
    "Narrative": "This according to the show bible."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Lower Decks",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "Ensign Boimler is voiced by Jack Quaid. Who are his famous parents?",
    "Answer 1": "Randy Quaid and Evi Quaid",
    "Answer 2": "Dennis Quaid and Meg Ryan",
    "Answer 3": "Kiefer Sutherland and Kelly Winn",
    "Answer 4": "Adam Sandler and Jackie\nSandler",
    "Correct Answer": "Dennis Quaid and Meg Ryan",
    "Narrative": "Jack Quaid is the son of Dennis Quaid and Meg Ryan. His uncle is Randy Quaid. Jack has also had a major role as Hughie Campbell in \"The Boys\" and Marvel in the film \"The Hunger Games\" ."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Lower Decks",
    "Description": "Production",
    "Question": "As an adult-oriented comedy, the show makes copious use of swear words,\n which are all bleeped out. Which of the following series also use swear\nwords, but are not bleeped out?",
    "Answer 1": "Strange New Worlds and\nPicard",
    "Answer 2": "Discovery and Picard",
    "Answer 3": "Discovery and Strange New\nWorlds",
    "Answer 4": "Voyager and Enterprise",
    "Correct Answer": "Discovery and Picard",
    "Narrative": "It's not clear why exactly the swear words in Lower Decks are censored. Perhaps because it's animated and a comedy and children may watch the show. This is just a guess\non my part."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Lower Decks",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "Jerry O'Connell voices the first officer (Ransom). What film did O'Connell\nco-star with Wil Wheaton (Wesley Crusher) of TNG in 1986?",
    "Answer 1": "Jerry Maguire",
    "Answer 2": "Stand By Me",
    "Answer 3": "Scream II",
    "Answer 4": "Kangaroo Jack",
    "Correct Answer": "Stand By Me",
    "Narrative": "Wil Wheaton portrayed Gordie Lachance, and Jerry O'Connell portrayed Vern Tessio. Their characters are part of a close-knit group of friends who go on an adventure to find\n the body of a missing boy."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Lower Decks",
    "Description": "Ships",
    "Question": "The Cerritos is named after a small California city. It's name is derived from\nthe Spanish word for what?",
    "Answer 1": "Big hills",
    "Answer 2": "Little hills",
    "Answer 3": "Small city",
    "Answer 4": "Big city",
    "Correct Answer": "Little hills",
    "Narrative": "The town's nickname is \"The Geographical Center of Southern California.\" The word itself is Spanish for \"Little Hills."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Prodigy",
    "Description": "Production",
    "Question": "This series was cancelled by Paramount+ in the middle of season 2. What\nstreaming service picked it up for the remainder of the second season?",
    "Answer 1": "Prime",
    "Answer 2": "Hulu",
    "Answer 3": "NetFlix",
    "Answer 4": "Disney+",
    "Correct Answer": "NetFlix",
    "Narrative": "After being canceled by Paramount+ with the second season still in mid-production, the series was picked up by Netflix to continue its run into the second season."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Prodigy",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "What captain from a previous series played a regular role in this series?",
    "Answer 1": "Archer",
    "Answer 2": "Janeway",
    "Answer 3": "Sisko",
    "Answer 4": "Picard",
    "Correct Answer": "Janeway",
    "Narrative": "Kate Mulgrew reprised her role from Voyager in this series. She played Hologram Janeway and Admiral Janeway."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Prodigy",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "Rok-Tahk belongs to Brikar race which is based on what type of lifeform?",
    "Answer 1": "Tree",
    "Answer 2": "Fish",
    "Answer 3": "Rock",
    "Answer 4": "Bird",
    "Correct Answer": "Rock",
    "Narrative": "This type of lifeform was later used in Galaxy Quest, which is basically a parody of Star Trek."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Prodigy",
    "Description": "Production",
    "Question": "How was this series filmed?",
    "Answer 1": "3D graphics",
    "Answer 2": "2D graphics",
    "Answer 3": "Stop motion",
    "Answer 4": "Hand drawn",
    "Correct Answer": "3D graphics",
    "Narrative": "This is the first Star Trek series to be 3D computer animated. The other two (The Animated Series and Lower Decks) were traditional hand-drawn animation and 2D computer \nanimation respectively."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Prodigy",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "Drednok, Jimmi Simpson's character, is loosely inspired by an evil robot\nfrom what film?",
    "Answer 1": "Hal 9000 from 2001: A Space\nOdyssey",
    "Answer 2": "Maximilian from The Black\nHole",
    "Answer 3": "Roy Batty from Blade Runner",
    "Answer 4": "Ultron from The Avengers",
    "Correct Answer": "Maximilian from The Black\nHole",
    "Narrative": "Maximilian is a large, red robot with a menacing presence, characterized by his rotating, bladed arms and a single glowing red eye."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Prodigy",
    "Description": "Ships",
    "Question": "What is the name of the ship in this series?",
    "Answer 1": "Protostar",
    "Answer 2": "Black hole",
    "Answer 3": "Pulsar",
    "Answer 4": "Neutron star",
    "Correct Answer": "Protostar",
    "Narrative": "The ship is discovered by a group of young alien characters who escape from a mining colony in the Delta Quadrant. They take control of the ship and begin their journey to\n explore the galaxy and search for a way back to the Alpha Quadrant."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "Prodigy",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "Which character becomes the de facto leader of the Protostar's crew?",
    "Answer 1": "Gwyn",
    "Answer 2": "Zero",
    "Answer 3": "Dal R'El",
    "Answer 4": "Murf",
    "Correct Answer": "Dal R'El",
    "Narrative": "Dal R'El is a rebellious and optimistic teenager who becomes the de facto leader and captain of the USS Protostar."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Voyage Home",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "Which of the following is significant about the \"punk rocker\"' on the bus and\nthe song that he was listening to?",
    "Answer 1": "The actor wrote the song",
    "Answer 2": "The actor sang the song",
    "Answer 3": "The actor was deaf",
    "Answer 4": "The actor was blind",
    "Correct Answer": "The actor wrote the song",
    "Narrative": "In addition to writing the song, the actor was also a writer for the film and an associate producer for the film."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Voyage Home",
    "Description": "Characters",
    "Question": "What were the names of the whales in the film?",
    "Answer 1": "George and Gracie",
    "Answer 2": "Burns and Allen",
    "Answer 3": "Fred and Ginger",
    "Answer 4": "Gene and Gilda",
    "Correct Answer": "George and Gracie",
    "Narrative": "Burns and Allen were an iconic American comedy duo consisting of George Burns and Gracie Allen. They began their partnership in the 1920s, performing in vaudeville\n before transitioning to radio, television, and film. George played the straight man, while Gracie's character was known for her ditzy and charmingly illogical humor."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Voyage Home",
    "Description": "What American aircraft carrier did Uhura and Chekov visit to find\nnuclear photons\"?",
    "Question": "USS Midway",
    "Answer 1": "USS Constellation",
    "Answer 2": "USS Enterprise",
    "Answer 3": "USS Coral Sea",
    "Answer 4": "USS Enterprise",
    "Correct Answer": "USS Enterprise",
    "Narrative": "Chekov and Uhura ask random passersby in San Francisco for directions to the \"nuclear wessels\", which obviously turned some heads."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Voyage Home",
    "Description": "Technology",
    "Question": "What material did Scotty \"invent\" in exchange for construction materials\nto contain the whales on the Bird-of-Prey?",
    "Answer 1": "Velcro",
    "Answer 2": "Gorilla glue",
    "Answer 3": "Duct tape",
    "Answer 4": "Transparent aluminum",
    "Correct Answer": "Transparent aluminum",
    "Narrative": "In reality, this material was actually invented 23 years later, in 2009."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Voyage Home",
    "Description": "Production",
    "Question": "What novel was the alien probe inspired by?",
    "Answer 1": "Rendezvous with Rama",
    "Answer 2": "Ringworld",
    "Answer 3": "Contact",
    "Answer 4": "Hyperion",
    "Correct Answer": "Rendezvous with Rama",
    "Narrative": "Written by Arthur C. Clarke, the story is set in the 22nd century and revolves around the discovery and exploration of a massive, cylindrical alien spacecraft, which is\n named Rama by the humans who encounter it."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Voyage Home",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "Dr. Gillian Taylor, portrayed by Catherine Hicks, went on to advocate what\n as a result of her study of whales for this film?",
    "Answer 1": "Marine biology",
    "Answer 2": "Anti whaling",
    "Answer 3": "Sea World parks",
    "Answer 4": "Marine conservation",
    "Correct Answer": "Anti whaling",
    "Narrative": "Catherine Hicks studied whales to help prepare for her audition and subsequent role. As a result, Hicks became inspired to become actively involved with anti-whaling efforts."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Voyage Home",
    "Description": "Characters",
    "Question": "What brand of beer did Kirk and Dr. Gillian Taylor order in the restaraunt\nscene?",
    "Answer 1": "Bud Light",
    "Answer 2": "Michelob",
    "Answer 3": "Coors",
    "Answer 4": "Corona Extra",
    "Correct Answer": "Michelob",
    "Narrative": "Kirk, being from the future and having no idea what to order, decided to order \"what she's having\"."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Voyage Home",
    "Description": "Production",
    "Question": "What was the last sound heard from the alien probe?",
    "Answer 1": "Thank you",
    "Answer 2": "I'm sorry",
    "Answer 3": "I understand",
    "Answer 4": "Thanks for nothing",
    "Correct Answer": "I'm sorry",
    "Narrative": "At one hour and 46 minutes, the last sound made by the alien probe as it turns away contains the English words \"I'm sorry\" in monotone in the lower frequencies."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Voyage Home",
    "Description": "Production",
    "Question": "This was the first Star Trek film to be shown where?",
    "Answer 1": "China",
    "Answer 2": "The Soviet Union",
    "Answer 3": "Japan",
    "Answer 4": "Mexico",
    "Correct Answer": "The Soviet Union",
    "Narrative": "This was the first Star Trek film to be shown in the Soviet Union, as it was screened by the World Wildlife Federation in 1987 to celebrate the country's ban on whaling."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Voyage Home",
    "Description": "Dedication",
    "Question": "What was this film dedicated to?",
    "Answer 1": "Space shuttle Challenger",
    "Answer 2": "USS Stark",
    "Answer 3": "Flight 191",
    "Answer 4": "Chernobyl Nuclear\n Disaster",
    "Correct Answer": "Space shuttle Challenger",
    "Narrative": "The film bore the dedication: \"The cast and crew of Star Trek wish to dedicate this film to the men and women of the spaceship Challenger whose courageous spirit shall\n live to the 23rd century and beyond..."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Voyage Home",
    "Description": "Production",
    "Question": "Although based at the Alameda Naval Station in Alameda, California, \nwhere was the scene with Chekov and Uhura sitting on the rocks looking\n at the aircraft carrier Enterprise actually shot?",
    "Answer 1": "Norfolk, Virginia",
    "Answer 2": "San Diego, California",
    "Answer 3": "Long Beach, California",
    "Answer 4": "Bethesda, Maryland",
    "Correct Answer": "San Diego, California",
    "Narrative": "The scene was shot at the North Island Naval Station located in San Diego, California."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Voyage Home",
    "Description": "Production",
    "Question": "This films sound was created using a new technology. What sound\ntechnology was used?",
    "Answer 1": "Dolby",
    "Answer 2": "THX",
    "Answer 3": "QSound",
    "Answer 4": "DTS",
    "Correct Answer": "Dolby",
    "Narrative": "This is the first film in \"Dolby Stereo Spectral Recording\" soundtrack."
  }
]